Chris Coenen Collection on General Tom Thumb MS254
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Printed ephemera, 1835 -- 1996; MS254.000866
  - Ad for Barnum's Managerie and Circus; The Eastern Argus, Portland, Me.; 5/31/55, 1855; MS254.001148 (Box 6)
    Ad for Barnum's travelling show with Tom Thumb
  - Article; The Midgets of Middleboro; The New England Home Magazine, 10/28/00, 1900; MS254.001149 (Box 6)
    Lengthy article with photos on the lives of the three midgets
  - Engravings; Lavinia's outfits before the wedding and article; Leslie's, 1/17/63, 1863; MS254.001150 (Box 6)
    Lavinia may have already been engaged to Charles Stratton at this time
  - Ad for Gentry Bros. Show, Stllwater Daily Gazette (Min.,) 6/17/07, 1907; MS254.001151 (Box 6)
    Lavinia and Primo worked with Gentry Bros.
  - Newspaper article about Gentry Bros. Show; Stillwater Daily Gazette, 6/17/07, 1907; MS254.001152 (Box 6)
    Article about the Gentry Show mentioning Primo, Ernesto and Mrs. Tom Thumb
  - Newspaper article about Tom Thumbs funeral; The Evening Chronicle; St. Louis, 7/20/83, 1883; MS254.001153 (Box 6)
    Describing Tom Thumb's funeral and Masonic Rights
  - Newspaper article, Tom Thumb Buried; 7/20/83, 1883; MS254.001154 (Box 6)
    Tom Thumb's funeral
  - Engraving of Tom Thumb taht accompanied an obituary, 1883; MS254.001155 (Box 6)
    From a photo by Bogardus
  - Newspaper article about the wedding; New York Observer 2/12/63, 1863; MS254.001156 (Box 6)
    Short article about the wedding
  - Article about Hop-O'-My Thumb at the Lyceum Theater, London; ILN,3/21/46, 1846; MS254.001157 (Box 6)
    Long illustrated article about the play starring Tom Thumb
  - Newspaper article, History oft the Marriage between Tom Thumb and Lavinia Warren; The Evening Telegraph, Philadelphia, 7/24/69, 1869; MS254.001158 (Box 6)
    Short article about their marriage
  - Newspaper ad for Dred, a play starring Tom Thumb; New York Tribune, 10/15/56, 1856; MS254.001159 (Box 6)
    Dred was a parody of Uncle Tom's Cabin with Tom Thumb playing Tom-Tit
  - Newspaper ad for the American Museum; New York Daily Tribune, 5/25/43, 1843; MS254.001160 (Box 6)
    Early ad for Tom Thumb at Barnum's Museum
  - Newspaper ad for the American Museum; New York Daily Tribune, 7/8/43, 1843; MS254.001161 (Box 6)
  - Newspaper ad for the American Museum; New York Daily Tribune, 10/7/43, 1843; MS254.001162 (Box 6)
  - Newspaper ad for the American Museum, featuring Lavinia Warren; New York Times, 2/6/63, 1863; MS254.001163 (Box 6)
    Ad just before the wedding
  - Obituary for Commodore Nutt; New York Clipper, 1881; MS254.001164 (Box 6)
    Engraving and obituary for Commodore Nutt who died in May, 1881
  - Newspaper ad for the American Museum; New York Daily Tribune, 7/8/43 II, 1843; MS254.001165 (Box 6)
  - Obituary and engraving for Tom Thumb; Harper's Weekly, 7/28/83, 1883; MS254.001166 (Box 6)
    Obituary and engraving from Bogardus photo
  - Newspaper; Burning of Newhall House, Milwaukee; Frank Leslie's, 1/20/83, 1883; MS254.001167 (Box 6)
    Large engraving of the hotel burning; Tom Thumb group were staying and narrowly escaped; Mrs. Sylvester Bleeker died; short article mentioning Tom Thumb and other engravings
  - Newspaper; parody of Newhall House fire and an ad; Frank Leslie's, 1/20/83, 1883; MS254.001168 (Box 6)
    Parody of diasater and an insurance ad with engraving of fire
  - Newspaper article; General Tom Thumb as Frederick the Great; ILN' 12/27/45, 1845; MS254.001169 (Box 6)
    Tom in costume as Frderick the Great
  - Newspaper; large engraving of Barnum's new museum with inset of Barnum; Harper's Weekly, 7/17/80, 1880; MS254.001170 (Box 6)
    Full page engraving of Barnum's new museum at Madison Square
  - Newspaper article; Tom Thumb's baby; The Globe, London, 10/6/64, 1864; MS254.001171 (Box 6)
    Short clip about the fake baby
  - Newspaper ad for PT Barnum's circus; New Haven Daily Palladium 5/5/81, 1881; MS254.001172 (Box 6)
    Nice ad for Barnum's circus in New Haven
  - Newspaper ad for Barnum's travelling show; The Hartford Daily Times; 6/16/51, 1851; MS254.001173 (Box 6)
    Nice ad for Barnum's early version of the circus with Tom Thumb
  - Newspaper ad for Barnum's traveling show; Hartford Daily Times 6/16/51 II, 1851; MS254.001174 (Box 6)
    Bottom of ad
  - Newspaper ad for competing circus; Storm Lake Pilot, 8/24/81, 1881; MS254.001175 (Box 6)
    Ad for circus competing with Barnum's
  - Newspaper article about Tom Thumb's baby; The Boston Cultivator, 8/5/65, 1865; MS254.001176 (Box 6)
    Article about the baby at Windsor Castle
  - Newspaper ad for Tom Thumb Show; Cleveland Morning Leader, 3/23/64, 1864; MS254.001177 (Box 6)
  - Newspaper ad for Tom Thumb show; Pennsylvania Inquirer, 11/14/43, 1843; MS254.001178 (Box 6)
    Early ad for Tom Thumb
  - Neswspaper ad for Barnum's American Museum; New York Tribune, 10/14/56, 1856; MS254.001179 (Box 6)
    Short ad mentioning Tom Thumb and the play, Dred
  - Newspaper article about Tom Thumb in England; The Albion, NY, 2/20/47, 1847; MS254.001180 (Box 6)
    Article, probably written by Barnum, about Tom Thumb's father in England
  - Newspaper article about Tom Thumb's visit to the Queen; The Albion, 1/16/47, 1847; MS254.001181 (Box 6)
    Article, probably written by Barnum, about the visit to the Queen
  - Newspaper article about Tom Thumb in Court; The Albion, 1/30/47, 1847; MS254.001182 (Box 6)
    Article, probably written by Barnum, about Tom Thumb's visit to Court
  - Newspaper article; Obituary for Mrs. Tom Thumb; The Boston Herald, 11/26/19, 1919; MS254.001183 (Box 6)
    Picture and story about Lavinia
  - Early photo of Dag of Tom Thumb as Napoleon; 1996 Calender from The Barnum Museum, MS254.001184 (Box 6)
    Copy of an early dag of Tom Thumb in the Barnum Museum Collection
  - Article, Mrs. Tom Thumb's Autobiography; Boston Sunday Post, 9/16/06, 1906; MS254.001185 (Box 6)
    Excerpts from Lavinias autobiography
  - Newspaper Ad for Tom Thumb;Lowell Daily Citizen and News, Lowell, Ma; 8/31/68, 1868; MS254.001186 (Box 6)
    Ad for Thumb shows
  - Newspaper ad for Tom Thumb; New Haven Daily Palladium;5/26/56, 1856; MS254.001187 (Box 6)
    Ad for Tom Thumb show
  - Ad for British soap featuring PT Barnum; The Graphic, 11/30/89, 1889; MS254.001188 (Box 6)
    Ad parodying the "Greatest Show on Earth"
  - Magazine graphic of Barnum's attractions, including Jumbo; The Graphic, 11/30/89, 1889; MS254.001189 (Box 6)
    Nice engraving of the acts in Barnum's circus, including a stuffed Jumbo
  - Newspaper article, My Life as a Showman by Barnum; The New York Family Story Paper; 5/1/88, 1888; MS254.001190 (Box 6)
    Excerpts from Barnum's biography
  - Article and photo about Lavinia; Peoples Home Journal, 1/17, 1917; MS254.001191 (Box 6)
    Short article and photo of Lavinia and Primo
  - Newspaper article on Tom Thumb; Newark Daily Advertiser, 2/24/47, 1847; MS254.001192 (Box 6)
    Barnum teases Tom Thumb's retirement even though he is only 9 years old
  - Millie-Christine, The Carolina Twins; hand colored newspaper illustration; Frank Leslie's Illustrated, 1866; MS254.001193 (Box 6)
    Millie-Christine encouraged the Magris to come to the US
  - Illustration of the burned second Barnum Museum, 1868; Frank Leslies Illustrated, MS254.001194 (Box 6)
    Hnad colored version of the remains of the second Museum; tiger being shot below
  - Illustration of the burning of the first Barnum Museum; 1865; Harper's, MS254.001195 (Box 6)
    Barnum's first American Museum burned in 1865
  - News article with photo of Lavinia advertising her movie, "The Lilliputian's Courtship" with Auger, the giant, 1915; MS254.001196 (Box 6)
    In 1915, Lavinia and George Auger starred in a two-reeler called The Lilliputan's Courtship; Pee Wee Players
  - Newspaper article about Lavinia's life; San Francisco Sunday Call, 1912; MS254.001197 (Box Large Map Case 3 Drawer 3)
    Lavinia recounts her life
  - Newspaper article about Barnum and the circus; The St. Louis Republic, 4/7/12, 1912 April 7; MS254.001198 (Box Large Map Case 3 Drawer 3)
    A little history of the circus
  - Illustration; the Happy Family exhibit, 1858; MS254.001199 (Box Large Map Case 3 Drawer 3)
    The Happy Family was a cage with various animals together
  - Close-up of the Happy Family, 1858; MS254.001200 (Box Large Map Case 3 Drawer 3)
    Close-up of the Happy Family
  - Illustration of the Lecture Room at the American Museum, 1858; MS254.001201 (Box Large Map Case 3 Drawer 3)
    Showing the theater and stage in the Museum
  - Illustration; Jumbo's Last Ride; woodcut of Jumbo the elepant in London; ILN, 1882; MS254.001202 (Box 13)
    Front page illustration of Jumbo just before being transported to the U.S. by Barnum
  - Print; framed; Tom Thumb and man, possibly his father, 1845; MS254.001203 (Box 16)
    Early print of Tom Thumb; man might be his father
  - Print; framed; Tom Thumb on table by Baillie, 1845; MS254.001204 (Box 16)
    Early print by Baillie that was copied in various forms
  - Print framed; Currier and Ives print of the marriage at Grace Church, 1863; MS254.001205 (Box 16)
    Print of the wedding group in 1863
  - Framed display piece of sideshow performers, including Mrs. Tom Thumb and baby; possibly from the Barnum Museum, 1865; MS254.001206 (Object 19)
    Twenty cdv's of performers; this may have been a display piece outside Barnum's Museum; many show the Barnum Museum logo on back along with tax stamps (1864-1866)
  - The Fairy Wedding printed photographs, circa 1920; MS254.001400 (Box 6)
  - Al G. Barnes Wild Animal Circus poster, 1960; MS254.001401 (Box 21)
    Circus World Museum print.
  - Adam Forepaugh and Sells Bros Big United Shows poster, 1960; MS254.001402 (Box 21)
  - The Barnum and Bailey Greatest Show on Earth poster, 1960; MS254.001403 (Box 21)
  - Ringling Bros World's Greatest Shows poster, 1960; MS254.001404 (Box 21)
  - Ringling Brothers and Barnum and Bailey Zing Zang Zoom subway poster, circa 1980; MS254.001405 (Box 23)
  - Grand Jumbo Now Returns to You framed calendar, 1923 November -- 1923 December; MS254.001406 (Object 25)
  - Framed photograph of Lavinia Warren, Tom Thumb, and unidentified man, autographs, and clipping, circa 1883; MS254.001407 (Box 17)
  - Lavinia Warren and Tom Thumb framed wedding photograph, circa 1863; MS254.001408 (Box 17)
  - Framed wedding photographs, circa 1863; MS254.001409 (Box 17)
  - Colored drawing of Tom Thumb meeting Queen Victoria, circa 1844; MS254.001410 (Box 17)
  - Newspaper clippings related to Tom Thumb, 1863 -- 1983; MS254.001426 (Box 1)
  - Tom Thumb postcards, circa 1990 -- 1995; MS254.001427 (Box 1)
  - Printed copy of Lavinia Warren photograph, circa 2000; MS254.001428 (Box 1)
  - "General Tom Thumb" article in Harper's Young People, an Illustrated Weekly, 1883 July 31; MS254.001429 (Box 1)
  - Sideshow Banners 2013 calendar, MS254.001430 (Box 1)
  - Ringling Bros. and Barnum & Bailey Circus souvenir program, 1980; MS254.001431 (Box 1)
  - Ringling Bros. and Barnum & Bailey Circus "The Amazing Mongolians" poster, 1991; MS254.001432 (Box 18)
  - Tom Thumb and his mother daguerreotype auction listing, 1998; MS254.001433 (Box 18)
  - Photographs of children reenacting "Tom Thumb wedding", 1938 -- 1950s; MS254.001434 (Box 18)
  - Greeting cards depicting Tom Thumb and Barnum's American Museum, circa 1990; MS254.001435 (Box 18)
  - Tom Thumb Circus toy advertisement, 1947 March; MS254.001436 (Box 18)
  - Signed photograph of Josh Evans as Tom Thumb, circa 1999; MS254.001437 (Box 18)
  - Vintage circus posters United States stamps, 2014; MS254.001438 (Box 18)
  - Tom Thumb and Wife print for use in magazine, circa 1962; MS254.001439 (Box 18)
  - Charles Stratton, "Gen. Tom Thumb" letterhead, circa 1880; MS254.001440 (Box 18)
  - The Only Original Mrs. General Tom Thumb and her Company of Liliputians program, 1898; MS254.001441 (Box 18)
  - Gen. Tom Thumb, Wife and Entire Troupe performance flyer, circa 1865; MS254.001442 (Box 18)
  - Count Magri, Countess Magri, and Baron Magri printed photograph, circa 1891; MS254.001443 (Box 18)
  - Printed drawings of Great Exhibition in Hyde Park, Polytechnic Institution, and Princess' Theatre, circa 1861; MS254.001444 (Box 18)
  - Charles S. Stratton, known as General Tom Thumb photograph mount, circa 1878; MS254.001445 (Box 18)
  - The Celebrated Tom Thumb & His Équipage framed print, circa 1846; MS254.001446 (Box 16)
  - Tom Thumb framed photographs, circa 1865; MS254.001447 (Box 16)
  - Michu and Juliana wedding poster, circa 1977; MS254.001465 (Box 4)
- Printed materials, 1828 -- 1953; circa 2021; MS254.001207
  This series contains printed materials related to Tom Thumb, including sheet music, advertisements, magazines, clippings, brochures, and booklets. Subjects of these materials include Tom Thumb, Lavinia Warren, phrenology, and P. T. Barnum.
  - Music sheet; General Tom Thumb and Lady; Grand Weddding March, 1863; MS254.001208 (Box 7)
    Sheet music dedicated to General Tom Thumb & Lady
  - Music sheet: Fairy Wedding Polka, 1872; MS254.001209 (Box 7)
  - Music sheet: The Female Auctioneer; published in England, 1865; MS254.001210 (Box 7)
    Partly written by Mrs. General Tom Thumb; English
  - Music Sheet; Presentation Polka;Rochester, NY, 1864; MS254.001211 (Box 7)
    The Strattons held a reception in Rochester, NY where they were presented with a gift at the Geo. Ellis Music Rooms
  - Music sheet: Minnie Warren Waltz; San Francisco, 1877; MS254.001212 (Box 7)
    Minnie passed away in 1878
  - Music sheet; Commodore Nutt Schottisch; with photo of Nutt, 1862; MS254.001213 (Box 7)
    Nutt had only recently joined Barnum at the Museum; with little photo of Nutt
  - Music sheet; Tom Thumb Polka; Edna Bump, arr., 1949; MS254.001214 (Box 7)
    Lavinia was a Bump; Benjamin Bump was a nephew
  - Music sheet; Tom Thumb March, 1949; MS254.001215 (Box 7)
    Sheet music
  - Music sheet: Tom Thumb, Novelty for Piano, 1939; MS254.001216 (Box 7)
  - Play; The Tom Thumb Wedding, 1898; MS254.001217 (Box 7)
    Child's Tom Thumb Play by Baker Company
  - Play; The Tom Thumb Wedding II, 1898; MS254.001218 (Box 7)
  - Play advertisement for "The Marriage of the Midgets", 1914; MS254.001219 (Box 7)
    Child's Tom Thumb Play by Rose
  - Cartercar advertising brochure with Lavinia and Primo, 1911; MS254.001220 (Box 7)
    Brochure from Cartercar company with testimonials from Mrs. Tom Thumb and Cont Primo Magri
  - Book woodcut of Tom Thumb and Haydon, artist, 1845; MS254.001221 (Box 7)
    Benamin Haydon exhibited at Egyptian Hall the same time Tom Thumb was exhibiting; he committed suicide over despair and jealousy of Tom's crowds
  - Egyptian Hall, Piccadilly, 1828; MS254.001222 (Box 7)
    Barnum exhibited Tom Thumb here in 1844
  - Building that replaced Barnum's Museum on Ann St. after the fire, 1870; MS254.001223 (Box 7)
    New building
  - Ad for Brady's Gallery across from Barnum's Museum and next to St. Paul's Church, 1860; MS254.001224 (Box 7)
    Barnum took many of his performers to Brady's, including wedding pictures the day before the marriage
  - Tom Thumb in various characters; Gallerie Dramatique; France, 1846; MS254.001225 (Box 7)
    French, hand colored litho of Tom Thumb
  - Woodcut of Tom Thumb's carriage; Illustrated London News, Auug. 1844, MS254.001226 (Box 7)
    Barnum announcing his new carrage to the public
  - Woodcut of Middleborough at the time of Lavinia's birth, 1845; MS254.001227 (Box 7)
    From a book of views of Massachusetts towns
  - Troops on parade near City Park with the Barnum Museum on the right, 1860; MS254.001228 (Box 7)
    From Gleason's Pictorial
  - Will Archie with Lillian Russell, 1910; MS254.001229 (Box 7)
    Will Archie promoted a movie with Lavinia and Auger, the giant in 1915
  - Barnunm's Herd of Elephants Tom Thumb's favorite, 1856; MS254.001230 (Box 7)
    Tom reode the baby in circus parades
  - Fire at Barnum's Museum, 1865; Le Monde Illustre, MS254.001231 (Box 7)
    French version of the fire woodcut
  - Article, in French, about the fire of 1865, MS254.001232 (Box 7)
    French article
  - Large woodcut of Tom and Laviania after the wedding, 1863; MS254.001233 (Box 7)
    Woodcut of the couple
  - Itallian woodcut of Tom Thumb in Europe, 1844; MS254.001234 (Box 7)
    Similar to some other woodcuts; from an Itallian paper
  - Article, in Italian, about 844, 1844; MS254.001235 (Box 7)
    Article in the Itallian paper that came with 844
  - Music sheet; Tom Thumb's Polka; 1847, MS254.001236 (Box 7)
    Danced by Him at the Boston Museum; composed by his pianist, W. Mardon
  - Barnum's Next "Greatest Show on Eart"; Judge Magazine, 1890; MS254.001237 (Box 7)
    Caricature of monarchs with Barnum
  - Broadway, NY- South From Park; Currier & Ives, 1850; MS254.001238 (Box 7)
    Reprint of a Currier & Ives print with Barnum Museum
  - Music sheet; Fairy Wedding Waltz, 1863; MS254.001239 (Box 7)
    Waltz by W Turner
  - French comic about Tom Thumb, 1866; MS254.001240 (Box 7)
    Colored comic of many of the engravings of Tom Thumb
  - Circus cut-out from magazine with Tom Thumb and Barnum, 1930; MS254.001241 (Box 7)
    Premiun section from a mgazine
  - Second wedding engraving; Leslie's Illustrated, 1885; MS254.001242 (Box 7)
    Hand colored engraving from Frank Leaslie's Illustrated Newspaper; Holy Trinity Church
  - The Tom Thumb Songster; small, early souvenir, 1850; MS254.001243 (Box 8)
    Unknown date but early, small souvenir of his songs
  - Guide Book for the Harry Hertzberg Circus Collection,San Antonio, 1942; MS254.001244 (Box 8)
    Guide to the collection containing many Tom Thumb artifacts
  - History of Animals and Leading Curiosities; Barnum's, 1874; MS254.001245 (Box 8)
    Booklet on Barnum's exhibits in his World's Fair
  - Magazine with article about Tom Thumb's visit to the Queen with an engraving of the poodle, 1857; MS254.001246 (Box 8)
    Children's magazine with a picture of the Queen's dog
  - Magazine with poodle, 1857; MS254.001247 (Box 8)
    Engraving and article
  - Phrenology almanac with article on Tom Thumb; 1848, MS254.001248 (Box 8)
    A phrenology analysis of Charles Stratton
  - Phreneology article about Tom Thumb, 1848; MS254.001249 (Box 8)
    Article and engraving
  - Magazine with engraved ad for Barnum's Museum, 1850; MS254.001250 (Box 8)
    Inside front cover ad for Barnum's Museum
  - Engraving for Barnum's Museum, 1850; MS254.001251 (Box 8)
    Ad
  - Brochure for Wheeler & Wilson Sewing Machines; wedding gift to Mrs. General Tom Thumb, 1863; MS254.001252 (Box 8)
    Description of the sewing machine
  - Brochure; Sketch of the Life of Charles Stratton, 1847, MS254.001253 (Box 8)
    Early descriptive brochure for Tom Thumb, 1847
  - Brochure; Sketch of the Life of Lavinia Warren, 1859, MS254.001254 (Box 8)
    Early descriptive brochure for Lavinia Warren
  - Brochure, bound; Sketch of the Life of Tom Thumb and Lavinia Warren; watercolor of Tom Thumb, 1865; MS254.001255 (Box 8)
    Descriptive brochure after the marriage; harbound with watercolor of Tom Thumb
  - Brochure; Sketch of the Life of General Tom Thumb and Lavinia Warren, 1867; MS254.001256 (Box 8)
    Descriptive brochure after the marriage
  - Booklet; Gen. Tom Thumb's 3 Years Tour Around the World, 1871; MS254.001257 (Box 8)
    Bleeker's description of the tour with engravings
  - Brochure; Sketch of the Life...,1874, MS254.001258 (Box 8)
    Descriptive brochure after the world tour
  - Brochure; The Lives of Tom Thumb and Wife, 1881, MS254.001259 (Box 8)
    Probably produced and sold for their circus tour
  - Brochure; Mrs. General Tom Thumb; 1906, MS254.001260 (Box 8)
    Descriptive brochure with biographical information and photos of the Magris; Lavinia does not want to be forgotten
  - Booklet; Grand Mamma Easy's General Tom Thumb, Nashua, N.H., 1849; MS254.001261 (Box 8)
    Early stories of Tom Thumb with engravings
  - Booklet; The American General Tom Thumb; NY, 1849; MS254.001262 (Box 8)
  - Booklet; Uncle Crow's Series, Gen. Tom Thumb, Philadelphis, 1849; MS254.001263 (Box 8)
  - Booklet; The Story That Never Grows Old; Benamin Bump, 1953; MS254.001264 (Box 8)
    Bump tells stories of Lavinia; B. Bump was Lavinia's nephew
  - Play; Tom Thumb; variation of Fielding, 1850; MS254.001265 (Box 8)
    Unknown date and not about General Tom Thumb
  - Book, miniature; 1.5" x 2"; Tom Thumb, 1846; MS254.001266 (Box 8)
    Miniature book about Tom Thumb
  - Book; Life of Thomas Thumb, 1849; MS254.001267 (Box 8)
    Book about Tom Thumb with engravings
  - "Barnum's American Museum" article in Illustrated News, 1853 October 29; MS254.001411 (Box 7)
  - "Barnum" Vanity Fair color print, 1889 November 16; MS254.001412 (Box 7)
  - "Life on Broadway" article from Harper's New Monthly Magazine, 1887 December -- 1878 May; MS254.001413 (Box 7)
  - Newspaper clippings related to "Freaks" film and Barnum performers, circa 1932; MS254.001414 (Box 7)
  - "The Ladies' World" magazine, 1901 March; MS254.001415 (Box 7)
  - Travelers Insurance calendar with image of Barnum's American Museum, 1996; MS254.001416 (Box Large Map Case 3 Drawer 3)
  - The Boston Sunday Post Pictorial Section, 1916 October -- 1917 March; MS254.001417 (Box 6)
  - Saint John Globe, 1918 October 31; MS254.001418 (Box 13)
  - "The Pigmies in Piccadilly," in Illustrated London News, 1880 November 27; MS254.001419 (Box 22)
  - Saint John Globe, 1919 December 06; MS254.001420 (Box 22)
  - Sketch of the Life, Personal Appearance, Character, and Manners of Charles S. Stratton, The Man in Miniature Known as General Tom Thumb, and His Wife, Lavinia Warren Stratton, Including the History of Their Courtship and Marriage, With Some Account of Remarkable Dwarfs, Giants & other Human Phenomena, of Ancient and Modern Times., 1867; MS254.001448 (Box 7)
  - Gen. Tom Thumb's Three Years' Tour Around the World, Accompanied by His Wife—Lavinia Warren Stratton, Commodore Nutt, Miss Minnie Warren, and Party., 1872; MS254.001449 (Box 8)
  - The New England Home Magazine, 1900 October 28; MS254.001450 (Box 8)
  - Hombres y Héroes: Barnum Embaucador Genial, 1993 March; MS254.001451 (Box 8)
  - Les Nains Célèbres Depuis L'Antiquité Jusques et y Compris Tom-Pouce par A. D'Albanès et Georges Fath, circa 1845; MS254.001452 (Box 8)
  - New England's Most Famous Impostors, Hoaxes & Frauds: Unforgettable Tales of Mad Scientists, Patent Medicine Miracles, Flagrant Fakers, and Foods That Aren't What They Taste (and that's no hoax), 1989 September; MS254.001453 (Box 7)
  - Lilliput, 1949 January; MS254.001454 (Box 7)
  - Kris Kringle Series: Tom Thumb, 1887; MS254.001455 (Box 7)
  - P. T. Barnum, Showman and Humorist. By Joel Benton, 1902 August; MS254.001456 (Box 18)
  - Tom Thumb picture book, circa 1930; MS254.001457 (Box 18)
  - M. G. M. Presents a George Pal Production, Tom Thumb comic book, 1958; MS254.001458 (Box 18)
  - Side-Shows, by William G. FitzGerald, circa 1880; MS254.001459 (Box 18)
  - The History of General Tom Thumb, circa 2010; MS254.001460 (Box 18)
  - True West magazine, 1976 December; MS254.001461 (Box 18)
  - The Illustrated London News, 1851 May 24; MS254.001462 (Box 1)
  - Lavinia Warren Bump genealogical records, Tom Thumb contracts, correspondence, and ephemera, circa 1926 -- 1990; MS254.001463 (Box 18)
  - Printed copies of scanned material, circa 2021; MS254.001467 (Box 27)
    This file contains printed copies of scans created by the donor. The majority of the material in the collection was scanned.
- Stereographs, 1858 -- 1892; MS254.001268